<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Former Site of Can I Blog Too</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Former Site of Can I Blog Too</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Implementation of Narcissism in R</title>
      <link>/2017/02/26/an-implementation-of-narcissism-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/26/an-implementation-of-narcissism-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This post is more an example of narcissism, but implementation has a nice technical ring to it.
Narcissism hasn’t been part of my every-day vocabulary, although it has been in the news recently. Lately we have been seeing discussions about narcissistic personality disorder, but that is not what I am talking about here. At least I hope not, because I’m talking about me.
Here’s the definition that fits this post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio of Projects</title>
      <link>/2017/02/17/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/17/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>One motivation for creating this blog was to display a portfolio of projects that I have worked on in the last year or so. I&amp;rsquo;ll list projects here. The plan is that eventually I will add pages that elaborate each project. I hope that publishing my projects on this site will nudge me to be a bit more systematic as I execute projects.
The Diary of Samuel Pepys Each morning I read an entry from The Diary of Samuel Pepys at a wonderful site created by Phil Gyford.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Flickr API from R</title>
      <link>/2016/07/03/using-the-flickr-api-from-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/03/using-the-flickr-api-from-r/</guid>
      <description>There used to be an Rflickr package, but it no longer seems to work. It was last updated in 2011. I had a lot of trouble googling information on how to access Flickr from R. This example really got me started. It is doing very different things that what I wanted to do, so it may be more useful than what I am laying out here, depending on your goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Note--Shiny Souvenir Map of Walks</title>
      <link>/2016/06/28/walks_map_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/28/walks_map_notes/</guid>
      <description>I have used RStudio’s Shiny to create a map page where I can display GPS traces and photos from walks I have done during the last five years.
The map is based on an example provided by Maarten Hermans in a blog post that he published last year. The map uses R htmlwidgets that provide access to the Javascript tool Leaflet. The trick is that I don’t have to know very much about either htmlwidgets or Leaflet to make this work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>