<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>British Walking on Former Site of Can I Blog Too</title>
    <link>/categories/british-walking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in British Walking on Former Site of Can I Blog Too</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/british-walking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>American Walker in Britain Part 3</title>
      <link>/2017/03/15/american-walker-in-britain-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/15/american-walker-in-britain-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Planning an Itinerary You have decided on where you are going to walk. Next you have to work out a detailed itinerary. For any trail covered by a Trailblazer book, it should contain a page that shows suggested itineraries for a relaxed, medium, or fast pace and for B&amp;amp;B&amp;rsquo;s, hostels or bunkhouses, and for camping. That produces a total of nine itineraries. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you are walking from B&amp;amp;B to B&amp;amp;B (rather than camping or a tour where some transport is provided).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Walker in Britain Part 2</title>
      <link>/2017/03/11/american-walker-in-britain-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/11/american-walker-in-britain-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a Path Obviously choosing a path is a matter of personal taste. In the first post I included some links where you could find ideas on where to walk. I&amp;rsquo;ll lay out some concrete possibilities here, just to get you started. Don&amp;rsquo;t take this as a prescriptive list.
Would you prefer walking on the coast or in the hills? If a multi-day route along beautiful seacoast appeals to you then the obvious possibilities are the South West Coast Path in Devon and Cornwall or the Pembrokeshire Coast Path in Wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An American Walking in Britain</title>
      <link>/2017/03/07/an-american-walking-in-britain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/07/an-american-walking-in-britain/</guid>
      <description>Since retiring in 2011, I have been on a binge of walking in the UK. I will try to offer some tips based on lessons I have learned. I doubt this would be of any use to someone raised in the UK. Much of what I would say here would be obvious or second nature. But lots of things weren&amp;rsquo;t obvious to me as an American and therefore a foreigner unfamiliar with the British countryside.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>